Lesson 23 Bird flight
鸟的飞行方法
First listen and then answer the following question.
听录音,然后回答以下问题.
What are the two main types of bird flight described by the author?
作者描述了鸟类哪两种主要飞行方式?
No two sorts of birds practise quite the same sort of flight;
没有任何两种鸟的飞行方式是相同的.
the varieties are infinite;but two classes may be roughly seen.
鸟的飞行方式千差万别,但大体上可分为两类.
Any ship that crosses the Pacific
任何一艘横渡太平洋的轮船
albatross: n.  信天翁
is accompanied for many days by the smaller albatross,
都会有一种小信天翁伴随飞行许多天.
which may keep company with the vessel for an hour
它们随船飞行一小时
without visible or more than occasional movement of wing.
也难得见其扇动一下翅膀
The currents of air that the walls of the ship direct upwards,
沿船体上升的气流
as well as in the line of its course,
和沿航线向前的气流
are enough to give the great bird with its immense wings
给这种巨翼大鸟以
sustenance: n.  支撑力
sufficient sustenance and progress.
足够的浮力和推力.
albatross: n.  信天翁, glider: n.  滑翔者
The albatross is the king of the gliders,
信天翁是滑翔飞行的鸟类之王,
harness: v.  利用
the class of fliers which harness the air to their purpose,
它能自如地驾驭空气,
but must yield to its opposition.
但必须顺气流飞行.
In the contrary school,the duck is supreme.
与滑翔鸟相对的另一类鸟中,数野鸭本领量高.
It comes nearer to the engines with which man has 'conquered' the air,as he boasts.
它更近乎全人类自夸"征服"了空气的发动机.
endow: v.  赋有
Duck,and like them the pigeons,are endowed with steel-like muscles,
野鸭及与它们相似的鸽子有天赋的钢铁般的肌肉,
that are a good part of the weight of the bird,
占了体重的很大一部分.
ply: v.  不断地供给
and these will ply the short wings with such irresistible power
这些肌肉以巨大的力量扇动短小的翅膀,
gale: n.  大风
that they can bore for long distances through an opposing gale
使这类鸟能顶着大风飞行很远的路程
before exhaustion follows.
才会疲劳.
partridge: n.  鹧鸪
Their humbler followers,such as partridges,
次于野鸭和鸽子的鸟,如鹧鸪,
propulsion: n.  推进力
have a like power of strong propulsion, but soon tire.
有相似的巨大推动力,但很快会疲劳.
You may pick them up in utter exhaustion,
你可捡到一些因筋疲力尽而摔下来的鹧鸪
if wind over the sea has driven them to a long journey.
如果海风驱使它们飞行很长距离.
The swallow shares the virtues of both schools in highest measure.
燕子充分兼有这两类鸟的长处,
It tires not,nor does it boast of its power; but belongs to the air
它既不疲劳,也不炫耀自己的飞翔力:在空中十分自如,
travelling it may be six thousand miles to and from its northern nesting home,
可以飞行6,000英里,去去归归于北方做窝的老家,
slip: v.  滑行
feeding its flown young as it flies, and slipping through a medium
一边飞一边喂养会飞的雏燕,它在气流中自由滑翔,
that seems to help its passage even when the wind is adverse.
即便是顶风时,似乎气流也在帮它前进.
Such birds do us good,
这些鸟对我们是有益的,
omen: n.  预兆
though we no longer take omens from their flight on this side and that;
虽然我们不再从它们的飞翔姿态来占卜吉凶,
and even the most superstitious villagers
连最迷信的村民
no longer take off their hats to the magpie and wish it good-morning.
也不再对喜鹊脱帽行礼,祝它早安了.